are you doing Louis Missouri here for no
bravotv today I'm filming here in
Chicago and I want to talk about the
food truck scene as you know the food
truck screen has been blowing up all
over the United States and Chicago is
really one of the last cities to really
fully embrace this trend I wonder where
my good friend shows up you bald Amenti
today and Jabez Giuseppe is known
locally as the Chicago pizza boss he
actually has the largest woodfired pizza
truck in the city this at this point as
you can see behind me it's pretty hard
truck to miss that big green white and
red Italian flag on the side Chicago
pizza boss doing brick oven pizza out on
Cheney and panzerotti why don't we go in
the truck take a look as he giuseppe's
around to talk to us maybe give us a
tour and tell us what the magic is
behind his truck come on follow me okay
so as I said today we're here which is
happy but lamenting this does that be
right here he's got this beautiful food
truck is it why don't you tell us about
about your truck here so I've got a have
24,000 pound truck with a 5,000 pound
brick oven in it
it's
Napoli 124 for Oh Bravo great oven it's
been it's been a pleasure to work with
quite honest how long have you had this
oven so this is going on - we're in
about two and a half years right now two
and half years I love I love this story
that you tell about two-and-a-half years
in a food truck is a lifetime in a
restaurant because of all the bouncing
around that the truck does and you know
the abuse that you know driving through
the city of Chicago yeah those are you
haven't been in Chicago before we got
some of the biggest potholes on earth
yeah size of the Grand Canyon you
actually lose a car inside so you hit a
couple potholes with the wood went out
like this you know you got those poop
brakes moving around yeah and it's
really it's really just a testament to
the quality that the ovens built I mean
I'm sure when Ford Oh Bravo designed
this oven they weren't thinking that
this thing was going to be bouncing
around in her truck for any amount of
time besides the delivery to where it's
going you know so you know I've had this
up and running for two and a half years
you know it's been operating flawlessly
the fire bricks are working really good
and I'm just really happy with it my
suggestion is if it could bounce around
in the truck for two and a half years
I'm still happy with it when it's just
sitting still inside your restaurant
it's probably gonna last you a long time
you said a mouthful right there that's
for sure and it's a testament I mean
this this is definitely work for
something you could actually push this
up and through its paces and I get
consistent results day in day out no
matter how extreme the conditions that
you're pushing right right so it's just
happy with your permission what I'd like
to do is I'd like to show everybody
watching actually my method for building
a fire inside a wood-burning oven what
it takes to actually get the foam for
the flames rolling and all and really
get that
Ferno inside that oven get the e on the
oven hot enough so that we can make some
pizzas for sure I'd love to make some
pizzas and win a world champion
pizzaiolo asked you if he could light
your fire in here oven I think you give
him all the permission in 600 so when I
was in Italy I went to school at the
Scala italiana pizzaiol in Catalina in
Venice and the headmaster the red cell
Roberta had this great little saying
that he would use all the time in the
morning he would start the fire in the
oven with a piece of newspaper but he
was always saying it's very important to
start the fire with a piece of newspaper
and it has good news on it as compared
to bad news and the pizzas always seem
to come out a little bit better during
the day when you use some good good
newspaper so what I've gone over here
I've actually stuck a little bit of
paper inside the fire what I'm doing is
I actually stuck the paper in on the
bottom of the logs and when you place
the logs into the oven I want to place
it so that the fire and the flame is
going to go up onto the raw part not so
much on the bark a lot of your moisture
is retained on this end and I feel that
you get a quicker burn it'll start
faster if you burn on this side first so
all my bread all my comics logs inside
the oven are actually all pointed in
words with the raw side exposed and
again a lot of this barb and these loose
pieces this will act as your kindling
inside the fire to allow them to burn
faster those start faster that's what
I'm going to do right now
okay so our fire is really nice and hot
right now in our oven is a perfect
temperature to go ahead and begin baking
which is empty why don't you go ahead
and actually show us through your
process show us how you walk throughout
a adult absolutely so we have two balls
here there are eight ounces for the
Neapolitan style jello and my method of
doing it is I get it into a flat
position like this where it's at a
relatively even thickness and then I use
three points of contact so I use these
fingers and my thumb and my other finger
and that's how I that's how I get it to
spread out a little bit more into a
bigger a bigger pizza roll so this is
actually something that's really good
here the way that Giuseppe is actually
pushing this dough out he's allowing the
the corner Tony that outside edge of the
the crust to actually not be disturbed
what you're actually doing in this
process here and I can actually show you
how to know in another dole bump when
he's talking about flattening out the
middle what we need is we need a we need
a basis to start to push that out so
when you when you're actually doing the
that beating of the crust what we're
doing is we're trying to make a seam so
that the air has nowhere to go it's
trapped inside that back to that
exterior edge if that's not disturbed
when it goes into the oven the pizza
actually give this really nice bit above
its spring and you'll get that neck the
technical role for that corner joint a
nice round round edge that's not very
typical to this style of pizza think
with the whoops out with the wood fire
in style pizza is that less is more you
want
everything to come together in your
mouth you want that you know be able to
taste the the amount of work that you
spend making the dough and I want to be
able to taste the sauce you want to
taste the mozzarella
okay just happy obviously you know what
you're doing over here these pizzas look
really bad for sure but the truth is in
the pudding here let's take a look at
how we did the border here looks really
nice
I got a nice golden color brown what
would you say our temperature is here on
the summit right now and it's that way
it's probably at the 556 50 range I
don't think it's any higher than that I
agree a lower temperature here is going
to give you more of a brown edge as
compared to running your oven hot or
like a Neapolitan style where you'd be
up to let's say 900 degrees and then you
get a lot more than the apollon
characteristic spotted charring around
the edge this pizza is a little bit
different because in that in there
respect because our temperatures a
little bit lower we're gonna have a lot
crunchy or crispy or crust then let's
say your typical Neapolitan dome the
other thing is also here take a look I
think we we got a really nice bake on
this you can see that you know it's
pretty typical of a out wood fire style
that burnt I'm sorry I did over there
man it looks good and then this one here
same thing I think we have a beautiful
beautiful crust that we can see that
these are a couple beautiful pizzas and
then Giuseppe is is a thing for machetes
this is his his pizza cutter here so
let's try one of these looks good in
case there's ever an attempt
yeah I'm the truck you could use it as a
weapon because you're right
you could hear that crispy crackle as
you cut into it that's a great sign in
Italy they eat the pizza I always say if
the if the pizza seems what you cut it
it means it's a good pizza then
crackling is what they call singing so
that's that's actually great these these
pizzas look from that phenomenal
Jeanette I really want to take my hat
off to you and say thank you for
allowing me to come on the trial today
through and thanks for named some pizzas
for you sure your beats are phenomenal
Cheers I'm so awesome at a little bit
every time I got the fish oil I may have
a former private TV I'm Leo Smith
ziering thank you very much for joining
us today have a great week all right bye
Mike